so you want to get internet fame and
learn how to model awesome things to
show off you're not alone
in this tutorial you will learn how to
model a viking x in our case the
leviathan x from god of war which can be
used for rendering or for your next game
project
we start to block out our handle with a
simple cylinder rotate it scale it in
the x-axis
bring it in position and delete the
outer faces
add some loop cuts with ctrl r and with
proportional editing select loops and
create an interesting shape for the axe
handle
[Music]
shrink it in the y axis and to fill up
the outer edge loop press ctrl f and
click grid fill
[Music]
let's now create a plane go in edit mode
and with vertex select mode we will
select and delete three words
now we have one to work with
press e to extrude the vertex to create
your shape for your x
you can connect two vertices by
selecting them and pressing f
start with a low vertex count and
decrease it as you need it
you can add additional vertices between
two the same way you do loop cuts
the shape does not have to be perfect
since we will later switch to sculpt
mode
[Music]
when you're done we will fill it out
filling out shapes is pretty simple you
can split most forms into circles in
order to fill them
the goal is to have a topology which
allows nice loop cuts let's inspect a
complex shape like the x
even complex shapes are circles watch
what happens when i move the vertices of
this x shape you have a circle and to
fill it out you can inset the outer
vertices and connect the inner so let's
fill out our eggs
[Music]
i will extrude the middle part to make
it more interesting
[Music]
when you filled out your shape you can
use vertex smoothing for a better
topology
for this stage i will add additional
loop cuts and try to have even sized
quartz
[Music]
alright let's make an axe out of our
plane add a mirror modifier and mirror
it by the z-axis
and with proportional editing i will
move my middle part to the left to give
it a curved shape
you can press g and use your mouse wheel
to control the radius
and with clipping turned on in the
mirror modifier you can move the
vertices of the sharp edge back
until they clip to the mirrored part
[Music]
i use smooth work this is quite often to
correct the flow of my words
now deactivate clipping and move all
vertices a tiny bit to the left to just
leave a little gap between the mirrored
pod select the outer edge loop turn on
clipping again and extrude it to close
the gap
and i forgot the bottom part oh man let
me quickly fix it
[Music]
like i mentioned smoothing out vertices
helps you to contain a smooth shape
use the settings to change the results
let's add some blue cuts for additional
topology and add a subdivision modifier
[Music]
now we have to sharpen our edges again
using the knife too
and when you ask yourself what the
is this guy doing there here's a quick
explanation
when you have a quack you can increase
the number of edges with loop cuts but
what if you want to leave one edge on
the left side but three on the right you
can use the knife tool by pressing k and
cut it so you have a single happy edge
on the left it's the same principle when
you use inset by pressing i on a face
but why should i care glad you asked
when you have a complex form with many
vertices doing loop cuts will result in
more pulleys with an uneven topology in
this case we have 308 with two loop cuts
it's 616 but with a nice cut it's just
360. if you still don't care here's a
use case when you add a subdivision
modifier your shape is rounded so you
have to add additional vertices to the
sharp parts you can be a noob and add
loop cuts or be a real gangster and cut
it in pieces
so since i'm pretty gangster i will do
this here
and here
and smooth out my birds
apply all modifiers add a
multi-resolution modifier and subdivide
it once or twice before we continue with
sculpting
i will first grab the red
wrap brush turn on y mirroring and
correct my shape a little bit but since
i'm already satisfied with the model and
there is not much to do i will increase
the number of subdivisions and start
adding the engravings to do so i will
pick the mask brush with full strength
and hardness and start to draw on my
model
you can change the radius of your brush
by pressing f
and by holding down control you can
switch between adding and removing mask
you can also switch between the brushed
strokes for example to draw straight
lines
[Music]
stroke stabilization is also useful to
draw nice curves
you can be pretty creative and take your
time this is sped up by like 20 times in
reality this is the real speed
[Music]
all right let's pick the mesh filter
with default settings
invert our mask and inflate our mask a
little
with the mask still active you can
smooth it out with a low strength
and after clearing the mask smooth it
out again
using the same process as before you can
add as many details as you want
[Music]
what is a viking x without ornaments
let's pick the inflate brush and open a
new texture
like this one
mask out our circle choose an anchored
stroke and apply our texture
you can find a link in the video
description for the ornament alpha
textures i'm using
[Music]
let's leave our extra now and continue
with the handle
here i will use dynamic topology with a
resolution of 80 to increase our level
of detail
and use the draw brush with the lowest
strength to mark the parts where i want
to add more detail
and again mask the parts you want to
edit and you straw smooth and grab to
sculpt your shape
[Music]
now to the art part
i don't know what else i can tell you
here what you didn't learn already the
horse took me about one hour to model
it's always important to start with a
rough shape and get more and more into
detail
use masks take your time use reference
images
check out the different brushes and the
use cases you have to practice a lot
when i started with 3d about one year
ago my sculpts look pretty cheap but now
after about 100 models i'm pretty
satisfied if you're interested in the
thought process leave a comment and i
will upload a time-lapse video
[Music]
so
[Applause]
to add tiny detail you need much more
pulls but this will also slow down our
system so i re-apologized the handle to
use the multi-resolution modifier and
transfer the details on my new model
add multi-resolution shrink wrap
set the target to the old model project
as rec mode check negative and subdivide
a bunch of times until all details are
transferred apply the shrink wrap
modifier and you're left with a high
detail model while still having a low
poly count on your original mesh
with a subdivision level of 5 i can now
add additional ornaments and even a wood
structure to our handle
be creative and test things out
[Music]
with my favorite brush the scrape brush
i will make the edges of our ax more
interesting and call it done
[Music]
now to the last part the leather
wrapping let's create a cylinder scale
it down
delete the upper and bottom face
and now we have to create a modifier
chain
start with subdivision
add shrink wrap and choose the handle as
the target select project above surface
and check negative
add a solidify modifier and adjust the
thickness
apply rotation and scale by pressing
ctrl a
and now just test different settings for
thickness and the shrink rib offset
[Music]
shade it smooth and add a loop cut to
the top and bottom
we should actually move the subdivision
modifier to the last position
now add a displace modifier
we will use a vertex group to control
the shape so create a vertex group and
select it in the modifier
[Music]
now go into weight paint mode by
pressing ctrl tab or on the upper left
side of the screen
you can now draw weights to set the
displays
[Music]
but first decrease the brushed string
and the displaced modifier should be
after the shrink wrap
you should now be able to add or
subtract weight to change the shape
now with all modifiers you can copy
paste the cylinder by pressing shift to
d
rotate it and create an interesting
wrapping
[Music]
and then just go into weight paint and
paint
and maybe you should increase the
mid-level strength
[Music]
let's check out our result
awesome i'm such a genius
and after uv unwrapping
baking the details
and some texturing and substance painter
this is the result with 15k pulleys and
fully game ready if you're interested in
the texturing process check out my bone
shield tutorial where i go more into
detail for the steps
alright
see
[Music]